Haymarket People's Fund Records
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Haymarket People's Fund Records
undated, 1971-1983.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Haymarket People's Fund.
1 linear foot.
The Haymarket People's Fund is an activist-controlled foundation committed to radical social change. It gives grants to grassroots groups throughout New England, which fight violence, poverty, and injustice, in an effort to empower oppressed communities.
MSS19950021
History
The Haymarket People's Fund is an activist-controlled foundation committed to radical social change. It gives grants to grassroots groups throughout New England, which fight violence, poverty, and injustice, in an effort to empower oppressed communities. It was co-founded by George Pillsbury in 1974 in Boston, Massachusetts. The Fund seeks to help workers, people of color, women, tenants, people with disabilities, students, the elderly, gay men and lesbians, environmentalists, veterans, and welfare recipients. The Fund operates through tax-deductible contributions, which are then distributed to qualified groups who apply for grant assistance. The Haymarket cannot fund social service of advocacy projects; groups with budgets of more than $100,000; groups that receive large government or corporate grants; alternative businesses or institutions such as food co-ops or alternatives schools; groups with no fundraising plans other than Haymarket; or groups that have existed for less than one year.
Scope and Content
The Haymarket People's Fund Records consist of the organization's files on its Connecticut activities from 1974 - 1983 [bulk, 1974-1981], primarily in Hartford and Southern Connecticut (New Haven area). Files contain applications and background information on organizations requesting grants in each specified district.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to civic, activist or alternative organizations that operate in Connecticut. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Arrangement
Series I: Hartford Files ( undated, 1974-1983 )
Series II: Southern Connecticut ( undated, 1971-1982 )
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Pillsbury, George.
Organizations:
haymarket People's Fund (Boston, Mass.)
Places:
Hartford (Conn.)--Societies, etc.
Subjects:
Social change--Connecticut.; Social action--Connecticut.; Social service--Connecticut.; Social advocacy--Connecticut.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The Haymarket People's Fund Records were donated by the organization to the University of Connecticut in 1990, as part of a program to deposit files in an archival repository in each state served by the Haymarket People's Fund.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Hartford Files, undated, 1974-1983
  - Association of Puerto Rican Farm Workers, 1974 (Box 1:1)
  - Blue Hills Citizen Action Group, 1982 (Box 1:2)
  - Committee to End Sterilization Abuse, 1978 (Box 1:3)
  - Citizens Research Education Network, 1982 (Box 1:4)
  - Coalition for Basic Human Rights, 1979 (Box 1:5)
  - Connecticut Anti-Apartheid Committee, 1980 (Box 1:6)
  - Connecticut Artjobs, 1976 (Box 1:7)
  - Connecticut's Citizen's Research Education, 1982 (Box 1:8)
  - Connecticut Women Against Sexual Harassment, 1980 (Box 1:9)
  - Connecticut Women's Educational and Legal Fund, 1983 (Box 1:10)
  - Connecticut Solidarity Committee, 1982 (Box 1:11)
  - Construction Workers, 1979 (Box 1:12)
  - Generacion Boricua, 1981 (Box 1:13)
  - Eggplant Media Productions, 1980 (Box 1:14)
  - Greater Hartford Community/Labor Alliance, 1982 (Box 1:15)
  - Greater Hartford Lesbian/Gay Task Force, 1982 (Box 1:16)
  - Greater Hartford Utilities Coalition, 1978 (Box 1:17)
  - Hartford Coalition for Justice in El Salvador, 1981-1982 (Box 1:18)
  - Hartford Food Systems, 1979 (Box 1:19)
  - Hartford Interval House, 1980 (Box 1:20)
  - Infant Formula Action Coalition, 1979 (Box 1:21)
  - Hartford Man's Collective, 1977 (Box 1:22)
  - Hartford's Peoples Bicentennial Commission, 1976 (Box 1:23)
  - Hartford Regional Board Minutes, 1981 (Box 1:24)
  - Hartford Woman's Center, 1978, 1981 (Box 1:25)
  - Hartford Office Workers, 1977-1978 (Box 1:26)
  - Hartford Women's Collective, 1980 (Box 1:27)
  - Hartford Women's Health Collective, 1976-1977 (Box 1:28)
  - Labor Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression, 1977-1981 (Box 1:29)
  - Neighborhood Women against Rape, 1978-1980 (Box 1:30)
  - The New Britain Citizen/Labor Energy Coalition, 1978-1981 (Box 1:31)
  - New England Regional Conference of National Organization of Legal Service Workers, 1978 (Box 1:32)
  - Northeast Coalition for the Liberation of Southern Africa, 1978 (Box 1:33)
  - Politics and Education, 1978 (Box 1:34)
  - Real Art Ways, 1979 (Box 1:35)
  - Student Educating for World Peace, 1981 (Box 1:36)
  - Trade Unionists for Progressive Action, undated (Box 1:37)
  - Urban Feminist Organization, 1979 (Box 1:38)
  - Vieques Support Committee, 1979-1982 (Box 1:39)
  - Women for Racial and Economic Equality, undated (Box 1:40)
  - The Work Project, undated (Box 1:41)
- Series II: Southern Connecticut Files, undated, 1971-1982
  - African Famine Relief Organization Main World Research, New Haven, 1976 (Box 1:42)
  - The American Independent Movement, 1975 (Box 1:43)
  - Angola Media Project, 1976, 1977 (Box 1:44)
  - Association of Religious Communities, 1977-1981 (Box 1:45)
  - New Haven Teachers Study Group, 1976-1978 (Box 1:46)
  - Bella Vista Tenants, 1977 (Box 1:47)
  - Center for the Study of Education and Politics, 1978 (Box 1:48)
  - Centro San Jose, 1979 (Box 1:49)
  - Community for Non-Violent Action, 1976 (Box 1:50)
  - Connecticut Committee Against Inflation and Unemployment, 1975 (Box 1:51)
  - Concerned Citizens for the Environment, 1981 (Box 1:52)
  - Connecticut Task Force on Abused Women, 1979-1980 (Box 1:53)
  - Connecticut Women's Educational and Legal Fund, 1980-1981 (Box 1:54)
  - Crisis Information/Action Center- New Haven, 1978-1981 (Box 1:55)
  - Dixwell Community House- New Haven, 1981 (Box 1:56)
  - East Haven Shore Line Association, 1979 (Box 1:57)
  - Emergency grants/miscellaneous data, New Haven, 1976-1980 (Box 1:58)
  - Feminist Union of New Haven, 1979-1982 (Box 1:59)
  - Gay Alliance at Yale/ Connecticut Gay Task Force, 1978 (Box 1:60)
  - Getting Action in Neighborhoods of New Haven, 1981 (Box 1:61)
  - Inner City Co-op Farm New Haven, undated (Box 1:62)
  - Men Against Domestic Violence, 1981 (Box 1:63)
  - Middlesex Community Paper, 1977 (Box 1:64)
  - MULANEH- Latin American Women of New Haven, 1979-1980 (Box 1:65)
  - New Haven Law Collective, 1976 (Box 1:66)
  - New Haven Peoples Center, 1981 (Box 1:67)
  - New Haven Public Power Project, 1977 (Box 1:68)
  - New Haven Street and Children's Theatre, 1977 (Box 1:69)
  - New Haven's Women's Center/ Ad Hoc Coalition to Fight the Family Protection Act, 1982 (Box 1:70)
  - New Haven Rape Crisis Center, 1981 (Box 1:71)
  - New Haven Regional Board, 1981-1982 (Box 1:72)
  - Office Worker's of New Haven, 1977-1982 (Box 1:73)
  - Peace, Education and Action Center/Wider City Parish, 1982 (Box 1:74)
  - People Acting for Change, 1971-1979 (Box 1:75)
  - People's Defense League, undated (Box 1:76)
  - Puerto Rican Coalition/Action for Bridgeport Community Development, 1982 (Box 1:77)
  - Puerto Rican Solidarity Committee- New Haven, 1976-1978 (Box 1:78)
  - Trident/Conversion Campaign, 1978-1979 (Box 1:79)
  - Progressive Education and Research Association, Inc.- New Haven, 1981-1982 (Box 1:80)
  - Research Associates for Policy Action- New Haven, 1977 (Box 1:81)
  - Reproductive Freedom Task Force, 1979 (Box 1:82)
  - Save Our Schools, 1981 (Box 1:83)
  - Sexual Harassment Case: Yale University, 1978 (Box 1:84)
  - STAND Community Radio Proposal, 1975-1977 (Box 1:85)
  - Tenants Representative Council, 1977 (Box 1:86)
  - Theatre of Light and Sound, 1981 (Box 1:87)
  - Teachers' Center- New Haven, 1977-1978 (Box 1:88)
  - Umoja Extended Family, 1977-1978 (Box 1:89)
  - United Farm Workers- New Haven, 1977-1978 (Box 1:90)
  - United Theater of the Americas, 1982 (Box 1:91)
  - Valley Woman's Center, 1980 (Box 1:92)
  - Women's Employment Resource Center, 1979-1981 (Box 1:93)
  - Women's Health Organizing Project, 1983 (Box 1:94)
  - Women's Health Services- New Haven, 1976 (Box 1:95)
  - Women's Transit Authority, 1980 (Box 1:96)